Toudou-san.
（土橋(どばし)）藤堂(とうどう)さん
（美沙(みさ)）あっ はい
Y-Yes?
Are you gonna be done with that soon?
そろそろ その作業終わりそう？
It'll be done today.
（美沙）今日中には
（土橋）じゃあ 次
Then you think you could start on another tire?
新しいタイヤの作業に入れる？
（美沙）えっ…
（土橋）できるよね？
No problem, right?
Yeah...
はい…
Musashino Animation
Episode 8 was finished last Saturday. It's scheduled to air on Thursday.
（本田(ほんだ)）
え～ ８話は
先週土曜に納品が終わり
木曜のオンエアを待つだけです
Episode 9 will be dubbed on Wednesday.
９話は あさって水曜にダビング
Episode 10 is outsourced, but the files will come on Friday and we'll do a full rush check.
10話はグロスですが
金曜に差し替えとオールラッシュ
Keyframe work for episode 11 is basically finished.
11話は原画作業が
ほぼ終わっています
Episode 12 dialogue will be recorded in two days.
12話は あさってアフレコ
All of that is pretty much on track. As for episode 13...
ここまでは まあ順調ですが
13話は… 最終話は…
The director still hasn't finished the storyboards for part B!
まだ監督の絵コンテＢパートが
上がっておりません！
For reals?!
（太郎(たろう)）
マジっすか？
It's highly unlikely we'll make it in time for the editing next week.
来週の編集
日程落とさないと厳しいな
We can't reschedule the VA recording though.
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
アフレコは落とせないぞ
声優陣のキープなくなるから
Their schedules are too tight.
Well, is there an ETA for the storyboards?
（あおい）
あの 見込みとしては
いつ上がる予定ですか？
That's what I'd like to know!
俺が一番知りたいよ！
We actually have to record dialogue to storyboards in the end, huh?
最終話にして アフレコ初
オールコンテ撮か
Hello.
Part A's storyboards are ready to be filmed for that.
Ａパートのコンテ撮の
準備はしてあります
Thank you for your call.
That should be it then...
（本田）
じゃあ 他になければ…
It's Katsuragi-san from Western Entertainment.
（興津(おきつ)）
ウエスタンエンタテイメントの
葛城(かつらぎ)さんがみえたそうです
Put it through to my room.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
ああ じゃあ 社長室に
ナベちゃんもね
Nabe-chan, let's go.
Will the final episode's storyboards ever be done?
上がるんですかね？
最終話の絵コンテ
That's how it is with an original work and nothing to adapt from.
（矢野(やの)）
オリジナル作品の
生みの苦しみだね
Even if the storyboards were done tomorrow, we still only have a little over a month until the deadline.
あした絵コンテが上がったとしても
納品まで あと１か月ちょっとだし
Quite the predicament, huh?
しびれる状況だな～
Good luck, Miyamori.
頑張れよ 宮森(みやもり)　応援してるぞ
Hang in there.
Quit acting like it's not your problem too!
（あおい）
無責任に言わないでください！
Barely over a month until the deadline? Keyframes alone take that long!
（ミムジー）
納品まで１か月ちょっとなんて
原画だけで終わっちゃうよ
Then come the tweening, painting, filming,
（ロロ）
その後に動画にして
仕上げして 撮影して
voice recording, and dubbing, then fixing this and that...
アフレコ ダビングして
いろいろ直して
Sounds tough!
（ロロ･ミムジー）
大変～！
How's it? Can you make it?
どう？　間に合う？
Not a chance!
（ロロ･ミムジー）
絶対無理！
What Do You Think Was the Message?
TV animation
Project Plan
By: Western Entertainment
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing, huh?
（葛城）
「第三飛行少女隊」か～
It's about both friendship and fighting.
It's really exciting.
（渡辺）
友情あり 戦いあり
熱くていいですよね この作品
Director Kinoshita was really into it too.
木下(きのした)監督もやりたがってて
It's quite a hit too. It's about to sell its millionth copy soon.
（葛城）
結構きてるよ これ
累計で100万部突破しそうだって
I guess it won't be easy going for us here.
やっぱり激戦ですかね？
The competition is really fierce.
いや 恐らく大争奪戦
だったら本気でいかないとね
Then we've got to give it our all.
Oi-chan!
（絵麻(えま)）おいちゃん
（あおい）ああ 絵麻
Ah, Ema?
I'm ready to work on the final episode next. When will things be ready?
次 私 最終話なんだけど
いつごろになりそう？
ごめん まだＢパートの
絵コンテ上がってないから
Sorry, but the part B storyboards still aren't done.
It's still gonna be a while.
もうちょっと先になりそう
Then could I help with episode 12?
じゃあ 12話のヘルプの仕事
もらえるかな？
Sure. I'll talk to Takanashi-san about it.
（あおい）
分かった　高梨(たかなし)さんに伝えとく
What have you been staring at for so long?
（太郎）さっきから何見てんすか？
（本田）うん？
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Oh, fancy seeing you checking this kind of stuff, Honda-san.
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
（太郎）
珍しいっすね 本田さんが
そんなの見てるなんて
Anime Pre-Order Toplist
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 5 (Bonus Talk Event Invitation and Lottery Ticket - Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Is Your Order a Turtle? Vol. 6 (With Bonus Event DVD - Limited Edition)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
A Certain Temple's Mummy Vol. 4 (Limited Edition)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
SSDRII2 (With Bookmark) (Limited Edition)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Amagi Amusement Park Vol. 1 Limited Edition (With Illustrated Container Box)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ball Watches Vol. 1 (With Drama CD)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Yosugi Roll Vol. 2 (Limited Edition with Event Lottery Ticket)
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Hey, we're 29th. That's not half bad!
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
おっ 29位
いい線いってんじゃないですか
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (Limited Edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
いや それはアニメだけで
But that's just out of anime.
Overall we've been bouncing around 100th.
トータルでは
100位を行ったり来たりなんだよな
Sales have improved because of the positive reviews,
but I wish we could sell even more.
評判よくて
だいぶ上がってきたけど
もうちょっと売れてほしいよな
It all comes down to the final episode, I think.
最終回が
左右すんじゃないっすか？
Don't you dare mention that to the director.
そんなこと 監督に絶対言うなよ
Spirit in the Lamp amuse 6
Exodus! Vol. 1 (limited edition)
Ekaterina of the Danzig Corridor Vol. 1
Any more pressure and we'd never get storyboards.
プレッシャーで
絵コンテ止まるからな
But you'll never make anything good if all you're thinking about is how well it'll sell.
でも売り上げなんて気にして
やりたいことがブレたら
いいもの作れませんよ
おっ…
たまには まともなこと言うな～
You say something smart every now and then.
えっ そうっすか？
Do I?
We should just stick to what we can do.
今 できることをやらないとな
（本田）
どうですか 監督？
How is it coming, director?
How much of the scenario is left?
あとシナリオ 何ページですか？
残り４ページ…
Four pages.
You're in the home stretch!
あとちょっとじゃないですか
But this is the hardest part!
そのちょっとが…
円(まどか)さんが“手伝おうか”って
言ってくれてますけど
Madoka-san's offered to help.
What do you say?
（本田）どうします？
（木下）イヤだ
I decline.
Then when are you going to finish?
じゃあ いつ上がるんですか？
ホントのこと教えてください！
Tell me the truth!
Please! We can't work with uncertainty!
お願いですから
僕らを安心させてくださいよ！
Um...
（木下）
あのさ
How would you define "interesting"?
面白いってなんだと思う？
Please, I'm not falling for that.
（本田）
その手には乗りませんよ！
I'm serious.
本気なんだけど
May I?
（なつき）ここ いい？
（美沙）はい
Sure.
今日 お弁当？
So that's your lunch?
Yeah, I cooked some pumpkin yesterday and had leftovers.
はい 昨日 カボチャ煮たの
余っちゃったんで
Would you like some?
あっ よかったら
Really? Then have a pork fry in exchange!
ホント？
じゃあ ハムカツと交換
やった～！　ハムカツ～！
Yay! I love fried pork!
It's great! So soft!
おいしい～！　ホクホク～！
The pork's great too.
ハムカツもおいしいです
美沙ちゃん ホイール
もう今日中で終わっちゃうんだ
So you're finishing the wheels today, Misa-chan?
早いね
You're fast, huh?
（美沙）
だいぶコツつかめてきたんで
I think I got the hang of it.
Not to mention I've been doing the same thing for a while now.
それに ずっと
同じことやってますから
It's been half a year since I joined,
and I'm still only doing wheels and tires.
入社してから半年以上
ホイールとタイヤばっかりですよ
I've only gotten to do interiors of cars for three years now.
私なんて３年くらい ず～っと
車の内装ばっかりやってるよ
Three years?
３年…
Make that five, doing the exterior of cars.
（三浦）
俺は５年 車の外装だな
The president keeps taking car jobs all the time.
社長 車の仕事ばっかり
取ってくるからね
He used to work abroad as a CG animator for Spark Story, right?
社長って 前は海外にいて
「ズーパーク ストーリー」の―
ＣＧクリエーターだったんですよね
（三浦）そう
Yeah.
The CG animals were so cute!
Just watching them move was a lot of fun!
あのＣＧの動物たち
すごくかわいくて
動きも楽しかったです！
Back in the day, we used to do stuff like that here too.
昔は この会社 そっち系も
やったみたいだったんだけどね
But for six or seven years it's been nothing but cars.
ここ６～７年は車だけだよな
Um, don't you want to do
something else from time to time?
（美沙）
あの さすがに他のもの
作りたくなりません？
I do, but you know...
（三浦）
なるけどさ 会社の方針だし
It's like company policy.
You see, we get paid a bit more than the average,
（なつき）
ほら うち
他に比べてお給料もいいし
休みも きっちり取れるし
and it's not hard to get time off.
Our benefits are pretty good, too.
福利厚生とかも
しっかりしてるじゃない？
Yeah, I applied here because of all those perks,
確かに私も条件いいなって思って
受けたんですけど
but having to do cars all day every day for years...
でも
このままじゃ あしたも あさっても
１年後も２年後も
車ですよね
Here.
（マネージャー）
はい これ
Episode 32
'sokay
It's a baseball show with the usual cast of mostly guys.
野球ものでレギュラーが
男の声優ばかりなんだって
But they need female voices for crowd noise,
and that's where you come in.
試合のシーンに女の子のガヤが
必要だってことで急遽(きゅうきょ)
（しずか･佐久間(さくま)）
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Bingo
"That bastard's laughing..."
"Good luck!"
Ryou
"!" (Echigo-kun!)
Incoming
Mii-chan
Shizuka
No subject
Can I visit the place you work
part-time at today?
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sending Mail
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Sent
Sorry,
I won't be there
today or tomorrow! (   ´□` ; )
Hello?
（美沙）あっ 今 大丈夫ですか？
（しずか）うん
Hey, is now a good time?
Sure.
So you'll be out until tomorrow? I hope you're not sick.
バイト休みって
体調でも悪いんですか？
（しずか）
ううん あした急に仕事が入って
No, it's just that I suddenly got work.
もしかして
アニメの仕事 来たんですか？
Doing anime?
It's just walla...
（しずか）
ガヤなんだけど
Walla? Are you playing a boy?
ガヤ！　少年役ですか？
役の名前じゃないよ
It's not the name of a character.
That's what they call voices used for crowd noise.
大勢の人のガヤガヤした声を
収録するのに呼ばれたの
I'm just one of many.
It's not even a named role.
その他大勢のうちの１人だから
役名もないし
But still! It's your debut!
そんな～　デビューは
デビューじゃないですか！
What show is it?
なんて作品なんですか？
Prince of Baseball.
（しずか）
「野球のプリンス様」
BasePri? That's awesome!
えっ 「やきプリ」？
すごいじゃないですか！
だから ちょっと
今日は練習しようかなって
I've been practicing for that today.
I see!
（美沙）
そっか 頑張ってくださいね
じゃあ
Good luck with it! Laters!
あっ みーちゃん
なんか話あったんじゃ…
Didn't you want to talk?
It's nothing important.
いえ 大したことじゃないんで
（しずか）
あした収録が終わったら
ごはんしようよ
We should grab something to eat after my recording tomorrow.
（美沙）大丈夫なんですか？
（しずか）うん
You're gonna be free after that?
Yeah!
Then I'll call Oi-chan-senpai and Ema-senpai too!
（美沙）
じゃあ おいちゃん先輩や
絵麻先輩にも連絡しときます！
Okay, see you tomorrow.
じゃあ あしたね
（美沙）
はい　ガヤ頑張ってください！
Yeah!
Good luck with the walla!
She's making her anime debut...
（美沙）
アニメデビューか
throwing Echigo a glance with a nasty grin
Base-side seats    Echigo notices Shinsaku's expression
Ryou cheers for Echigo as he walks to the batter's
box from the next batter's circle, but he's startled by
Echigo's steel expression is
Echigo stands in the box glaring at his opponent
Shinsaku answers with a smile
What should I say?
なんて言えばいいのかな？
頑張って！　うん…
"You got this!"
"You can't lose, got that?"
負けたら承知しないから！　うん…
"Good luck!"
ファイト～！　ああ…
Prussia
Studio
This is where I had that awful audition.
ここはオーディション落ちたところ
いや 今日でトラウマ脱却だ
I guess this is my chance to redeem myself!
よし！
16:00 ~ 21:00
TV Anime
Prince of Baseball
#32 AR
The event tomorrow starts at 10, so I'll go to pick you up by 8.
（マネージャー）
あしたのイベントの入り時間
10時なので
８時までに
サカウエに迎えに行きますね
（永井(ながい)）
はい
Okay.
やっぱ主役張る人は
キラキラしてるね
It's like all the big-name VAs have halos over their heads.
行こうか
You ready?
I'm Sakama Hiromi from Akaoni Production.
赤鬼(あかおに)プロダクションの
佐久間ひろみです
Thank you for having me.
よろしくお願いします
（スタッフたち）
よろしく～
Thanks for coming.
I'm from Akaoni Production too. I'm Sakaki Shizuka.
同じく赤鬼プロダクションの
坂木(さかき)しずかです！
若輩者なので ご指導ご鞭撻(べんたつ)
I'm a beginner,
so please help me improve!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Asugawa Gen
Sound Director
（明日川）
ここね 土禁
No shoes allowed in here.
ああ…
申し訳ございませんでした！
I'm terribly sorry!
（葛城）
それで
「第三飛行少女隊」なんですけど
I bet you've already gotten a lot of offers
Hantou Tatsuya
Yotaka Books - Editor
for an anime adaptation of 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
もうどこかからアニメ化の
話 来てますよね？
（半藤）
いろいろ問い合わせは
頂いております
There have been some inquiries indeed.
Just as I expected.
そうですよね
これから力を入れていきたい
タイトルなんで
We definitely want to invest further in the franchise.
We'll be direct: would you contract us for making the anime?
ずばり うちで
やらせていただけないでしょうか？
Pardon me for sounding rude,
but could Musani pull it off?
失礼ですけど
ムサニさんでできますかね？
But of course!
もちろんです！
いいスタッフを集めて
We'll have great staff on it who will all do fantastically.
全力でやらせていただきたいと
思っています
The director would be Kinoshita Seiichi.
監督は木下誠一(せいいち)を
予定しておりまして
Ah, the Boing Boing Paradise guy?
ああ「ぷるんぷるん天国」の
Would he make this show boing too?
この作品も
“ぷるんぷるん”しちゃうんじゃ？
Definitely not. Our currently airing Exodus has enjoyed consistent quality and positive reviews.
いえいえ
今 やってる「えくそだすっ！」は
クオリティーも安定してて
おかげさまで評判になってまして
Oh, that's director Kinoshita's work too?
あっ あれ木下監督なんですか
Exodus is much better than I expected.
「えくそだすっ！」
意外と面白いですね
あっ ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much.
The director's great for projects like 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
「第三飛行少女隊」は
監督の得意分野でもありますし
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションの
総力を挙げて
Musashino Animation's very best would be at your disposal.
作らせていただきますんで
ぜひ！
This is a matter I can not decide by myself.
う～ん… でも
僕の一存では判断できないんで
上へ上げてみてからで
I'll have to discuss this with my superiors.
（葛城･渡辺）
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much for your consideration.
We're done with the main dialogue!
（明日川）
はい 本線は以上で～す
Background voices, please!
続いて ガヤ下さい
Cuts 100 to 113.
え～ 100カットから113カットまで
お願いします
Bottom of the 9th, 6-point game, 2 outs.
９回裏６点差で２(ツー)アウト
MC up to bat. No one on base.
ランナーなしで主人公の打席
Chances are he loses, but you still hope for the comeback. Cheer him on.
負けるかもしれないけど
なんとか打たせたい
…という気持ちで
応援してあげてください
We'll trim it down to fit, so just keep going. And rolling.
キューランプ出します
少し長めに下さ～い
You can't just lose, got that?!
負けたら承知しないから～！
Hold on! You in the red dress, you're overdoing it.
赤い服の彼女
ちょっと張り切りすぎかな
（笑い声）
（しずか）すみません！
I'm sorry!
Take one step back!
（明日川）
１歩下がって！
Once more!
はい じゃあ もう一回
お願いしま～す
Go! You can do it!
いけ！　頑張って！
Hit!
打って！　負けないで！
諦めないで～！
You can win! Don't give up!
Okay! Thanks!
（明日川）
はい オーケーです
ありがとうございました！
（声優たち）
ありがとうございました～！
Thank you!
Ah, Zuka-chan-senpai!
（みどり）あっ ずかちゃん先輩
（しずか）おっ
You're already here?
（美沙）
早かったですね
Yeah.
Oi-chan-senpai and Ema-senpai are still at work.
（みどり）
おいちゃん先輩と絵麻先輩は
まだ仕事だそうです
How did recording BasePri go?
（美沙）
「やきプリ」のアフレコ
どうでした？
The MC's Nagai Tsukasa-san, right?
Did you see him?
主役 永井つかささんですよね？
会えました？
Yeah.
うん　私より年下なのに
オーラがあって…
He's so charismatic even though he's younger than me.
It must be because he's done so many lead roles.
何本も主役やってるからかな
（みどり）
へえ～
You got to work with amazing people like him!
ずかちゃん先輩
そんなすごい人たちと一緒に
アフレコやったんですね
Yeah...
（しずか）うん
（美沙）うまくいきました？　ガヤ
Did it go well?
It was over in a flash.
いや～ 一瞬で終わっちゃって
Not to mention I got scolded for standing out too much.
おまけに ちょっと目立ちすぎて
怒られちゃった
That's rough.
ああ 厳しいっすね
But it was a great experience overall, right?
でも いい経験に
なったんじゃないですか？
I suppose so.
まあ そうだけどね
I think you're getting there, step by step.
なんか 少しずつ
前に進んでる感じですよ
I have no idea how to work towards becoming a scenario writer.
ずかちゃん先輩は
私なんて どうやって
シナリオライターになったらいいか
全然分からないんで
この先 まったく見えませんよ
I don't know how I'm gonna get there.
Knowing exactly what's waiting for you isn't always that nice.
でも 先が見えすぎて
気持ちが萎えることもあるよ
ＣＧの会社に入って
夢に近づいたと思ったけど
I thought I got closer to my dream by joining a CG company,
but nowadays I feel like I've only gotten further away from it instead.
最近 逆に
夢から遠ざかってるような
気がするんですよね
Why's that?
（しずか）
どうして？
ずっと車の部品しか作ってなくて
I'm only making parts of cars, and we've got this kind of work lined up for three more years.
会社には３年先まで
同じ仕事が入ってるし
社長に直訴してみたら
いいんじゃないですか？
Why don't you just ask your boss?
Ask them to let you do something else.
他の仕事やらせてくださいって
Rii-chan, a total newbie who hasn't even been around a year can't make demands like that.
りーちゃん
入って１年もたってない新人が
そんなこと言えないよ
そうなんですけど
でも このまま この会社にいたら
That's right.
But if nothing changes I'll be making nothing but wheels for the next three years.
３年後もホイール作ってる自分しか
思い描けなくて
Still better than not knowing if I'll have a job at all in three years.
それ言ったら 私なんか３年後
仕事あるかどうかも
分かんないんだよ
Not that I've got so many now.
まあ 今も ほとんどないんだけど
I know what you mean.
同じくっす
Will we really be able to make
The Divines together sometime?
ホントに いつか みんなで
「七福陣」作れるんすかね～
It's from Ema.
絵麻からだ
She can't get off work yet.
やっぱり仕事 終わんないって
Oi-chan-senpai can't come either.
おいちゃん先輩も
やっぱり来れないって
She says she's busy researching something.
調べ事が はかどんないって
She's looking up if diesel engine trains pass Musashisakai or not.
武蔵境(むさしさかい)の駅に
ディーゼル車が通ってるかどうか
調べてるって
Diesel engine trains?
ディーゼル車？
Maybe they came up in her episode.
（美沙）
担当してる話数に
それが出てくるんですかね？
へえ～ じゃあ 私も
調べ物 手伝おっかな
I should help her look into them!
She always treats me to tea, and it's not like I have anything important to do!
いつも部屋で
お茶とか ごちそうになってるし
何より暇だし
Oi-chan and Ema are both working so hard.
おいちゃんも絵麻も
頑張ってるな～
They actually get to make something cool.
何かを作ってるって感じがして
I'm jealous.
（美沙）羨ましいです
（みどり･しずか）うん？
（美沙）
へえ～ プリウスに20インチの
マグネシウムホイール入れてるんだ
20-inch magnesium wheels on a Prius?
At that size, they really fill up the wheel well, giving the whole car a more solid look.
やっぱり20インチだと
ホイールスペースの
隙間が埋まるから
車体全体が締まって見えるな
Sounds like you're pretty into your job, Mii-chan.
みーちゃんも
仕事頑張ってるんだね
（美沙）えっ
（みどり）ああ 啄木(たくぼく)です
Yup, you know what they say.
"The grass is always greener on the other side!"
“友がみな われより
えらく見ゆる日よ”です！
I've got great news for you all.
（立石）
え～ 今日は皆さんに
いい報告があります
We get to work on the game Grand Speed 2.
「グランスピード２(ツー)」という
ゲームの仕事を
やらせていただくことが
決定しました
The first was done at a different CG company,
but the developers went out of their way to request us.
１(ワン)は違うＣＧ会社がやってましたが
メーカーがわざわざ
うちでお願いしたいと
言ってくれたんです
It's because of the splendid work you've done.
Tateishi Kouichi
Super Media Creations - President
これも我が社の実績が
認められたからです
Now keep it up and make sure every tire and screw is perfect!
これからも みんな―
タイヤ１つ ネジ１つに
魂を込めて頑張りましょう
痛っ！
（立石）そのタイヤ 頑丈だろ？
（美沙）あっ…
That tire's built like a tank, huh?
It's designed for premium comfort.
プレミアムコンフォートタイヤ
だからな
グリップ性能も
ウエット性能も高くて
Its grip and traction when wet are both great, and it always gives a smooth ride.
乗り心地もいいし 静かなんだ
It's quiet, too.
What happened, Toudou-kun?
何があった？　藤堂君
The line director, Dobashi-kun, is high on you.
ラインディレクターの
土橋君が褒めてたよ
He said that while your polygons were quite rough at first, you've improved quite a bit.
最初はポリゴンの流れが
汚かったけど
今は すごくキレイになったって
Um...
（美沙）あの…
（立石）うん？
Will I ever get to do any other CG besides modeling wheels?
私 ホイールの
モデリングだけじゃなくて
他のＣＧも
やらせていただけるように
なれるんでしょうか？
Depending on your skills and talents,
it's a real possibility.
この先 能力や適性に応じて
他のＣＧも作ってもらう
Motion, perhaps.
モーションをつけたり…
But it would still only be cars, right?
（美沙）
それは全部 車なんですか？
Yes.
車だ
Will there be any work other than for cars?
（美沙）
その 自動車以外のＣＧの仕事は…
This company's not even a decade old yet,
うちは まだ
創立して10年に満たない会社だ
but in the industry, we're already the go-to name for cars.
でも業界内では
自動車だったら
スーパーメディアクリエイションズ
It's what we've poured our passion into.
そう言ってもらえるようになった
Thanks to that, we have a steady flow of work.
それは自動車という無機物に
情熱を注いできたからだ
そのおかげで
安定して仕事をもらえている
Nowadays, we're all the way up to fifty employees.
Can you imagine how hard it is to pay fifty employees every month?
社員も50名に増えた
50人に毎月毎月 給料を払うのは
大変なことなんだよ
You mentioned other CG.
Did you have anything particular in mind?
他のＣＧと言うが 具体的に
何かやりたいことがあるの？
I was thinking I'd like to make an anime again,
with my friends from my high school club.
私は高校の時
アニメーション同好会で
一緒だったみんなと
またアニメを作りたいと思ってて
What kind?
（立石）
どんな？
A show that could warm everyone's hearts.
Both children and adults.
子供も大人も楽しめるような
元気になれる作品を
If you've got a goal, then you should think about what exactly you have to do in order to achieve it.
目標があるんなら
そのためにどうしたらいいか
一度 しっかり考えてみたら？
If you can't quite picture your own future,
you won't be able to start getting there,
何をやるにしろ この先の自分が
具体的に思い描けないと
no matter what your goal is.
始まらないだろ？
This just doesn't feel right.
なんか違うんだよな～
What doesn't feel right?
（本田）
何が違うんですか～？
The last scene.
ラスト
You're already on the last scene?
（本田）
ラストで
詰まってるってことですか？
I did it according to the scenario,
シナリオどおりに
やろうとしたんだけど
but I'm not sure if this ending is good.
この決着でいいのかって
The Tracy girls are cornered by the police.
警官隊に追い詰められた
トレイシーの面々
Akane rides the bike from the carrier off a ramp and into the ocean.
バイクに乗ったあかねたちは
空母から海にジャンプ
There's no way they could survive that, is there?
これ あかねたち
絶対 助からないよね？
You were the one who said the ending should be Hollywood-like!
監督が言ったんじゃないですか
アメリカン･ニューシネマっぽく
やりたいって
And that's what I had in mind at the scenario meeting...
シナリオ打ちの時は
そう思ったんだよ～
but there aren't any carriers in Japan in the first place.
でもさ 大体 日本に
空母なんてないよね？
もう空母のデザインは
発注したじゃないですか
But we've already ordered the designs for it!
Have you?
そうだっけ？
しないと
間に合わないですから
It wouldn't have been available on time otherwise.
Um...
（木下）あのさ
（本田）なんですか？
What is it?
How mad would you be if I said I wanted to...
（木下）
ラスト変えたいって言ったら…
change it?
（木下）怒る？
（本田）えっ？
I don't think anyone could accept that ending.
（木下）
だってさ～ このラストだと
見てくれた人は
納得できないと思うんだよ
I definitely can't!
何より俺が納得できない！
So can I change it?
変えてもいいかな？
If the director doesn't end the show properly, who will?
監督が この作品を着地させなくて
誰がさせるんですか
So what are you changing it to?
で… どう変えるんですか？
俺 この作品で
何を伝えたかったんだと思う？
What do you think was the message? What was I going for?
知らねえよ！
How would I know?
I guess that's right.
だよね　知らないよね
Of course you wouldn't...
はあ～ 分かりました
Fine.
I'll call the writer, Maitake-san.
ライターの舞茸(まいたけ)さんに
連絡してみます
Maitake Shimeji
Script Writer
I see.
（舞茸）
なるほど
I never would've guessed you were still on storyboards.
まだ絵コンテをやってるとは
思いませんでした
I'm terribly sorry, but would you please help us?
すみません　申し訳ないんですが
相談に乗ってください
分かりました
Sure.
Let's see then...
さて 監督がこの作品で
Director, what were you trying to make the show primarily about?
一番やりたかったことは
なんですか？
Moe.
（木下）萌(も)え？
（本田）それは違うと思います
Don't just spout whatever.
You wanted some pretty girl action show at first, right?
最初は確か
美少女アクションやろうって
ことだったんですよね？
That's true.
そうなんだけど…
Why did you name it Exodus in the first place?
そもそもタイトルを
「えくそだすっ！」にしたのは
どうしてでしたっけ？
What are Akane and her friends running from?
あかねたちは
何から逃げてるんでしょう？
The police.
警察？
舞茸さんが聞いてるのは
そういうことじゃなくて
Maitake-san doesn't mean that literally.
しんどい現実から
逃げてるのかな？
Probably the harshness of reality.
And what do they gain at the end of their flight?
（舞茸）
逃げた末に あかねたちは最後
何を手に入れるんでしょうね？
A chance to sing?
歌うこと… かな？
I thought so.
（舞茸）
そうですよね？
Even while they're on the run, they keep talking about how they want to stand on a stage
逃げている間
あかねたちはずっと
“また３人でステージに立ちたい”
and sing together again.
“歌いたい”って
言ってましたもんね
But they're cornered...
でも あかねたち
もう追い詰められてるし
When we discussed the story,
you said Akane is very trusting of people.
そういえば本読みの時 監督よく
“あかねは
すぐ人を信じちゃう子だよ”って
言ってましたよね？
Did I?
（木下）
そんなこと言ったっけ？
You did. I still remember that quite clearly.
言ってましたよ
僕 それがすごく
頭に残ってるんですよね
So why does Akane keep trusting people?
なんで あかねは
人を信じるんですかね？
I don't know. That's just how she is.
分かんないけど
それが あかねなんだよ
信じて裏切られて
そのせいで窮地に陥るんだけど
She trusts them, but she's betrayed and falls into great peril.
Somehow, she doesn't lose faith.
それでも誰かを信じ続ける…
あっ そっか
もしかしたら俺
I see.
Maybe I wanted to make a story about believing in others no matter what happens.
“どんな時も人を信じる”
ってことが やりたかったのかな？
Akane never wavers, and in the end all her dreams come true. Sounds like a great ending.
誰かを信じてきた
あかねの希望がかなったら
いいラストになりますよね　きっと
I got it.
そうだな
Even after bitter betrayal,
she keeps trusting in others.
裏切られても人を信じてきた
And behold, the light in their hearts is a beacon for the future!
そんな あかねたちのよさが
ラスト 未来をひらく！
Excuse me.
（あおい）
失礼しま～す
We're dropping the carrier.
（木下）
空母は やめだ
In the end, Tracy returns to the Musashino Dome.
（木下）
最後トレイシーは
武蔵野ドームに戻ってくる！
They all wanted to sing there once again.
なぜならこの場所で もう一度
歌うことを望んでいたからだ！
誰もいないドームで
あかねたちは歌いだした！
In the empty dome, they start singing.
They stream their final concert to the whole world over the Internet.
彼女たちは その最後の
コンサートを全世界に配信する！
But cops surround and lock down the venue.
だがドームは警官たちに包囲され
完全に封鎖された！
Tracy still doesn't stop singing.
それでもトレイシーは
歌うのをやめない！
Thousands of people rush to the arena.
やがて ネットを見た何万人もの
人々が会場に押し寄せる！
People who don't care about rumors and just want to hear them sing come in droves!
それはウワサに惑わされず
純粋に彼女たちの歌を
聴きたいと思った人々だ！
People who believed in them,
even when they were on the run, come too!
逃亡中に出会い 彼女たちの無実を
信じる人々もやって来た！
They force the cops to retreat as they enter the hall!
警官隊を蹴散らし
会場になだれ込む！
That's when the song nears its end!
やがて曲はエンディングを迎え
The lights fade slowly...
ゆっくり照明が落ちていく
And that moment...
…と その瞬間
All the cops open fire at once!
警官たちの
一斉射撃が始まった～！
The only light in the dark is the flash of gunfire!
闇に光るのは
マズルフラッシュの嵐！
Then comes the deafening silence.
そして 長い沈黙があった後
再びスポットがつく
The lights come back on...
…と 舞台のセリに奈落の穴が
And there is a trapdoor open on the stage.
Akane and her friends are gone!
あかねたちは消えた！
あかねたちは舞台裏を走った！
They're backstage, running!
But the perimeter is crawling with cops.
The situation is hopeless!
だが表は警官で取り囲まれて
絶体絶命のピンチ！
Just when all hope seems lost,
ついに捕まってしまうのかと思った
その時に
a cowboy shows up with a hundred horses!
カウボーイが
馬を100頭連れて現れた～！
Howdy.
（カウボーイ）
ハウディ
He and all the fans help them escape!
（木下）
彼女たちの逃亡をみんなが助ける！
But the cops are still on their heels.
追いかけていた警部までもだ！
Then the horses grow wings with sonic engines and—
そして馬に羽が生え
羽からソニックエンジンが
出てきて…
This is a bit too far out there.
さすがに それは―
荒唐無稽すぎます
（木下）あう…
And what about all the false charges?
えん罪は晴れないんですか？
Forget about those!
（木下）
それはテーマじゃない
How does it end?
じゃあ ラストは？
They arrive at the Chofu airport on horseback. A plane comes...
（木下）
馬で調布(ちょうふ)飛行場にたどり着いた―
あかねたちの前に飛行機が現れ…
and off they go!
飛び乗る！
出来た！
Done!
Indeed it is.
出来ましたね
That's it! It's done!
おっしゃ～！　完成だ！
Thank you so much for your help!
（本田）
すみません 本当に助かりました
It's nothing.
（舞茸）
いや
I just came to play catch.
僕はキャッチボールを
しに来ただけですから
Horses?
馬？
Horses running?
馬が走る？
A hundred of them?!
100頭も？
よし！
Let's do this!
Hello, this is Musashino Animation.
（丸川）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
Thank you for your patronage!
ああ いつもどうも
What? You got some good duck meat?
えっ いい鴨(かも)肉が手に入った？
Next time on Shirobako: "Just One More."
次回
「ＳＨＩＲＯＢＡＫＯ(シロバコ)」
Just One More